# **ASHIF EQBAL**

DevOps & Cloud Engineer

**Email:** <u>ashif8984@gmail.com</u> **Phone:** +91-7522933227

Location: Hyderabad, Telangana, India









### Summary

8.5 years of IT Experience in managing complex environments in Linux & Windows across on-prem and AWS. Highly- motivated employee with desire to take on new challenges. Strong worth ethic, adaptability and exceptional interpersonal skills. Adept at working effectively unsupervised and quickly mastering new skills.

### **Work Experience**



Sr. DevOps Engineer | EY GDS - India LLP

July 2022 - Present

- Leading team of 5 Engineer to Develop, Test, deploy self-service application in VMware
- Actively working with a Banking Client to deliver efficient, quality, and resilient services
- Working with teams to develop, test and merge Infrastructure Code in Ansible & terraform
- Involve in sprint planning meetings to understand & capture requirements and work closely with SMEs, Stakeholders
  and teams to deliver product & services every sprint/iteration
- Create and maintain Service Document & Developer guide for services delivered
- Actively work in release management activities for code promotion and production deployments.

# aws

### Cloud Engineer | Amazon Web Services (AWS)

October 2021 - July 2022

- Work closely with AWS Customers to issues related to AWS Cloud Services
- Design and test CloudFormation template that best suits customer requirements
- Replicate customer issues locally and find the root cause to help customers
- Provided assistance to customers over chat/call/email to resolve queries
- Providing the best and cost-effective solution to customers for application onboarding & migration to AWS.



### DevOps / SRE Engineer | Amdocs

May 2020 - September 2021

- Automated the Application Deploy/Restart across multiple Enterprise Applications using Jenkins and
- AnsibleJenkins Job creation for Onboarding various Applications and APIs
- Maintaining different Jenkins Server for Dev, Test, UAT and Prod environments
- Responsible for resolving Build & Deploy Errors in Java Projects using Maven and ANT

# Sr. Infra Developer (DevOps) | Cognizant

August 2019 - May 2020

- Written script for Build, Unit-Test, Code-Coverage, Packaging and running it in Jenkins le
- Created Jenkins Multiple Branch pipeline using Pipeline Groovy scripts for Code-Review, Build, Unit testing, Code Coverage, packaging, Nexus-Upload, deployment to Dev/UAT/Pre-Prod Environments
- Created Form-Bases CD Jobs for Deployment using Jenkins
- Build a CI and CD pipeline using Groovy script in Jenkins
- Created CloudFormation template for Provisioning Infrastructure on AWS
- Application setup under IIS, app pool and web sites creation and maintenance using Chef Cookbook
- Migrated around 114 MSO Code components in Stash and created CI/CD Pipeline.

# TATA CONSULTANCY System Engineer | TCS

Lune 2015 - August 2019

- Created and scheduled a weekly archival database job to reduce application outage and downtime
- Managed and Optimized server health and performance using Log rotation and archival jobs
- Maintained the monitoring and alerting of production infra using Cloud Watch service
- Automation of daily tasks using PowerShell, Bash and Python scripts
- Generated PowerShell tool for sending maintenance alerts to stakeholders and business users
- Worked on handling Linux related Activities High Memory, Disk Usage, CPU Utilization
- Configured and Managed release build for Staging and Production Environments
- Written Ansible-Playbooks and Roles for Application Deployment and restarts.

#### Education

### Gandhi Institute of Engineering & Technology

B.Tech | Electronics & Instrumentation (2011 – 2015)

#### **Skills**

- Versioning Tools: Git/GitHub, SVN, Perforce
- CICD: Jenkins, GitHub Actions, Azure DevOps, AWS CICD Tools, Ansible, Ansible Tower, Nexus, JFrog Ansible, Nexus, JFrog
- Build Tools: Maven, MS-Build
- Ticket Tracking: Jira, ServiceNow, Azure Boards
- Container Tool: Docker, Kubernetes
- Operating System: Linux, Windows
- Cloud: AWS, VMWare Cloud
- Languages: Python, JavaScript, Typescript
- Scripting: Shell, PowerShell, Python
- Database: MS-SQL, My-SQL
- Monitoring: New-Relic, Nagios
- Infrastructure Automation: Terraform, CloudFormation

# Certification

- AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- HashiCorp Terraform Associate
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900

# **Declaration**

I, Ashif Eqbal hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: Hyderabad, India